newton.k12.ma.us 2017-06-12

# Privacy Policy / Overview

This Privacy Statement is intended to inform users about the general approach the Newton Public School system uses in collecting, using and disseminating user information via http://www.newton.k12.ma.us

Newton Public Schools is sensitive to the issue of confidentiality in online dealings and is committed to protecting individual privacy.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, please contact our site coordinator in the Information Technology Department or by mail to:

Newton Public Schools  
Attention: Information Technology Department  
100 Walnut Street  
Newton, MA 02460  
 **  
What data do we collect automatically and why?**  
When you visit http://www.newton.k12.ma.us our web server automatically recognizes your domain name, but not your e-mail address. We collect the domain name and monitor general site use and traffic patterns to improve our web site and services. Newton Public Schools uses web server logs to collect data for metric purposes. Examples of the types of data collected on the logs are IP addresses, referral pages, date and time of site access, and site/pages visited. We may use collected data to customize the content and/or layout of our pages for each individual visitor. If you choose to submit information to us via a web form or email, we will use the information you provide only to serve your needs. When we collect sensitive information though online forms, we use SSL technology, which protects data transferred over the Internet by encrypting information so it cannot be accessed or changed. You can confirm that you are on a page protected by SSL by making sure that the URL begins with https://

 **Do we use Cookies?**  
Cookies are small data files placed on your hard drive by a website server when you visit. Newton Public Schools may use cookies for tracking purposes or to make the site easier to use. Cookies are currently the only way to effectively identify a unique anonymous visitor and understand how they navigate our web site. An anonymous visitor to our site remains anonymous in all cases. We do not attempt to identify visitors if they do not voluntarily submit personal information to us. With most Internet browsers, you can erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Cookies offer enhanced functionality to the user, but whether you allow a cookie to be placed on your computer is up to you!

 **Do we collect personal information?**  
In some cases, the Newton Public School system requests personally identifiable information from you in order to satisfy the underlying transaction or purpose of your accessing the Site. Examples of personally identifiable information include names, e-mail addresses, mailing addresses, and the like. Please note that we do not consider any and all information we receive to be private, however NPS will never give or sell any of your information.

 **When would we disclose your information?**  
We do not rent, sell, or trade any personally identifiable information about you (such as your name or e-mail address) to outside organizations for marketing or solicitations.

 **What about external links?**  
For the convenience of our site visitors, Newton Public Schools may provide links to third party web sites that are external. These web sites are not operated or controlled by Newton Public Schools, and Newton Public Schools is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such external web sites.

 **Photo Content**  
Occasionally a photo of a particular school activity such as a science project, sporting event, or other activity may be posted. This may involve posting a picture showing a student or group of students or a sample of student work. If a student’s photo or work is used, we will not disclose the following:

Student Last Names  
Personal Information

In addition, documents will not include information that indicates the physical location of a student at a given time other than attendance at a particular school or participation in an activity.

 **Disclaimer**  
Newton Public Schools may from time to time revise its privacy statement without notice to individuals. Visit this page often so you are aware of any revisions. We will not use your existing information in a manner not previously disclosed. This web site is not a contract. This statement is for informational purposes only and should not be considered the basis of a contract between the Newton Public Schools and any individual or party.

 **Copyright**  
The contents of all materials on these web sites are copyrighted by Newton Public Schools unless otherwise indicated. All rights reserved by Newton Public Schools.
